<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Administration on GridDB</title>
    <link>http://example.org/administration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Administration on GridDB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/administration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Supported OS, Platforms and System Requirements</title>
      <link>http://example.org/administration/6-1_supported-os-platforms-and-system-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/administration/6-1_supported-os-platforms-and-system-requirements/</guid>
      <description>Supported Environments The following Linux distributions are tested and will work with GridDB
 OS: Red Hat Enterprise Linux 6.2 / 6.3 / 6.4 / 6.5 (x86_64) CentOS 6.2 / 6.3 / 6.4 / 6.5 (x86_64)  Hardware Requirements As GridDB is a scale-out database, it is easy to add more machines to the cluster to increase both computing power and storage space simultaneously. Some basic hardware requirements look like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sizing and Scaling</title>
      <link>http://example.org/administration/6-2_sizing-and-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/administration/6-2_sizing-and-scaling/</guid>
      <description>GridDB is a scale-out database that unlike a conventional DB, careful system design and sizing is not required in order to achieve non-stop operation. However, the following points should be considered as guidelines in the initial system design.
 Memory usage Number of nodes in a cluster Disk usage  The estimation method is explained in sequence below.
Functions to increase the capacity by using external storage devices such as SSDs etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing</title>
      <link>http://example.org/administration/6-3_installing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/administration/6-3_installing/</guid>
      <description>The following chapter will discuss how to install GridDB (Standard Edition). Instructions for installing on the cloud can be found below
On Premises The following 3 RPM packages are needed when installing a GridDB node. Place these packages anywhere in the machine.
Package name
File name
Description
griddb-server
griddb-server-X.X.X-linux.x86_64.rpm
The start and other commands for the GridDB node module and server are included.
griddb-client
griddb-client-X.X.X-linux.x86_64.rpm
One set of operating commands except start node is included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Editions</title>
      <link>http://example.org/administration/6-4_upgrading-the-editions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/administration/6-4_upgrading-the-editions/</guid>
      <description>Follow the procedure below to update the software.
 Stop the cluster Stop the node Make a backup copy of the definition file, database file and event log file Update the software Start the node Configure the cluster  An example of the command execution in a machine in which the nodes have been started is shown below.
[Command execution example]
$ gs_stopcluster -u admin/admin $ gs_stopnode -u admin/admin $ cp -rp /var/lib/gridstore/data /xxx/shelter # copy just in case $ cp -rp /var/lib/gridstore/log /xxx/shelter # copy just in case $ cp -rp /var/lib/gridstore/conf /xxx/shelter # copy just in case $ su # rpm -Uvh griddb-server-Y.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration from Other Databases</title>
      <link>http://example.org/administration/6-5_migration-from-other-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/administration/6-5_migration-from-other-databases/</guid>
      <description>In the GridDB export/import tools, to recover a database from local damages or the database migration process, save/recovery functions are provided in the database and container unit.
In addition, there is also a function to link up with RDBs, and RDB data can also be collected and registered in GridDB.
Overview In a GridDB cluster, container data is automatically arranged in a node within a cluster. The user does not need to know how the data is arranged in the node (data position transmission).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cluster Administration &amp; Operations</title>
      <link>http://example.org/administration/6-6_cluster-administration-operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/administration/6-6_cluster-administration-operations/</guid>
      <description>The cluster operation control command interpreter (hereinafter referred to gs_sh) is a command line interface tool to manage GridDB cluster operations and data operations.
The following can be carried out by gs_sh.
 Operation control of GridDB cluster  Definition of GridDB cluster Starting and stopping a GridDB node and cluster Status, log display  GridDB cluster data operation  Database and user management Collection, trigger display Index setting, deletion Search using a tql/sql   [Memo]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring &amp; Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>http://example.org/administration/6-7_monitoring-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/administration/6-7_monitoring-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>This chapter describes the troubleshooting procedures of GridDB. It contains information on how to resolve problems which occur when constructing and operating a GridDB’s system.
This chapter is written for developers, users and system administrators responsible for GridDB’s operation management.
The following subjects are covered in this chapter.
 Introduction Verification of the circumstances under which problems occurred: explains how to check the detailed circumstances (log file). Countermeasures to be adopted when problems occur: contains a list of expected problems and their countermeasures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuning</title>
      <link>http://example.org/administration/6-8_tuning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/administration/6-8_tuning/</guid>
      <description>After installation, the following settings are necessary in order to operate GridDB.
 Network environment settings Cluster name settings  GridDB settings are configured by editing 2 types of definition files.
 Cluster definition file (gs_cluster.json) Node definition file (gs_node.json)  The cluster definition file defines the parameters that are common in the entire clusters.
The node definition files define the parameters for the different settings in each node.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>