<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Modeling on GridDB</title>
    <link>http://example.org/data-modeling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Modeling on GridDB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/data-modeling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Modeling Basics</title>
      <link>http://example.org/data-modeling/4-1_data-modeling-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/data-modeling/4-1_data-modeling-basics/</guid>
      <description>GridDB is a unique Key-Container data model that resembles Key-Value. It has the following features.
 A concept resembling a RDB table that is a container for grouping Key-Value. A schema to define the data type for the container can be set. An index can be set in a column. Transactions can be carried out on a row basis within the container. In addition, ACID is guaranteed on a container basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Modeling Using GridDB</title>
      <link>http://example.org/data-modeling/4-2_data-modeling-using-griddb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/data-modeling/4-2_data-modeling-using-griddb/</guid>
      <description>Storing Data in Collection
The flow of storing data in a Collection is shown below. First, if there is no Collection to store data in, create a new Collection following the procedure below:
 Get a GridStore instance. Create a Collection.  You can store data in an existing Collection with the following procedure:
 Get a GridStore instance. Get a collection. Set operation parameters Create indexes. Create values to be stored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/data-modeling/4-3_modeling-relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/data-modeling/4-3_modeling-relationships/</guid>
      <description>4 Data Modeling &amp;gt;
4.3 Modeling Relationships What are Modeling Relationships? Though GridDB does not employ strict schemas overall, it is important to have some semblance of foresight when dealing with the cluster&amp;rsquo;s data. Utilizing data to its potential is the end-goal when choosing a database, and so when setting up the data for the first time, it is important to make certain decisions.
Relationships between data and how they are organized are very important for both analytics and performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/data-modeling/4-4_possibilities-and-variations-of-data-models-in-griddb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/data-modeling/4-4_possibilities-and-variations-of-data-models-in-griddb/</guid>
      <description> 4 Data Modeling &amp;gt;
4.4 Possibilities and Variations of Data Models in GridDB T.B.D </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>